Shyam Kumar R Featured

Java Full Stack Developer - Immediate joinee



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 11 Month(s)

Current Company: OnPassive Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Chennai Highest Degree: BTECH [Computer Science and

__, Engineering]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Project Management, Data

Management, HTML, CSS, Maven, ENOVIA, SQL, Java, MQL, TCL, Javascript, JQuery, MVC, Spring, Bootstrap, JDBC, JSP

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Software Professional with 3 years of overall experience and 2 years of experience in Enovia Matrixone/3DExperience PLM. High Proficiency over Java Programming well versed with Java / J2ee. Programming with TCL, MQL, Spinners, HTML,CSS and JavaScript.

Work Experience

OnPassive as Software Engineer Sep 2020 to Till Date

Working as a full stack developer in designing ecom website

Hinduja Tech Ltd. as Consultant Software Engineer Feb 2018 to Sep 2020

Project # 1
Project Title
3DExperience(V6 R2015x)
Client Name
Ashok Leyland Technical Center- Chennai
Duration
1 Year 1 Month (From August 2018)
PLM Tools Used
Enovia V6 R2015x
Other Technologies
Spinners

Description:

This is a project to implementation of ENOVIA V6 R2015x for mechanical PLM Company.

My Responsibilities

Worked on Engineering Central implementation as per 3DExperience Schema Analyzing the functional requirements & developing the requirements.

Involving in Bug Fixing.

Project # 2
Project Title ALFES
Client Name Ashok Leyland
Duration 6 Months (From Feb 2018)
PLM Tools Used Eclipse, PostgreSQL
Technologies Java, HTML, CSS, JS, SQL, Bootstrap, Spring MAVEN
Framework

Description:

ALFES is like to implement a front-end application for their Simulation Tools.

Client would require an easy user interface application to facilitate a business change.

They would prefer that the testing and simulation engineering team to directly manage the simulation process.

Using alter PBS as a main backend for further tasks.

My Responsibilities

Understanding Requirement Specifications and Design Documents.

Worked on front end code for developing screens using HTML, CSS, JS, BootStrap etc.,

Worked on some important modules in Java using Spring Maven.

Worked on integration of roles in Enovia Tool to the application using TCL Language.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2016

PG: BTECH (Computer Science and Engineering) in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
С	
JAVA, J2EE	
HTML, CSS	
SQL	
JavaScript	
MQL	
TCL	
JSP	
BOOTSTRAP	
Spring Maven	
Eclipse, PostgreSQL	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Telugu	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: Ashok Leyland M & HCV

Client: Ashok Leyland

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2018 - Aug 2019

Project Location: Ashok Leyland Technical Centre Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 4 Skill Used: MQL, TCL, JAVA, JPO , JAVASCRIPT, JSP, CORE JAVA, ADK .

Role Description: Working as Enovia PLM developer. Doing enhancement and bug fixing in the project. Project Details: This is a project to enhancement of ENOVIAV6 application for mechanical PLM Company.

Project Title: ALFES Client: Ashok Leyland

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Feb 2018 - Aug 2019

Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Team Size: 5

Project Details: Scope of the project is to develop preprocessor for frame analysis and Simulation form configurator tool. Simulation form: The users will enter input in excel and upload or enters through the screen. If the inputs passes validation, the application will communicate with the backend excel templates and other tools through Altair PBS tool. The graphical output willbe displayed to the front-end. If the user is fine with visualization output, the approval life cycle is initiated and word document is generated. Frame Analysis: the application will generate forms for Element Size, Points, Side Member Elements, Cross MemberElements, Gazet/Flitch, Spring, PID, Section, Material, Tyre Stiffness, Mass, UDL and Cleave Plate. The user could either upload these data using excelfile or fill the form directly. The application must do validation and generate consolidate excel file before submitting to Altair PBS. The output will be excel files and images which needs to be displayed.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Category: General

Countries: India

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time